avfc.co.uk 2019-04-11

# Privacy Policy

Summary of our privacy policy.

_To see the full table on a mobile device without scrolling, rotate your mobile to landscape_

**Question** | **Summary answer  ** | **For more information, see:**  
---|---|---  
What is the purpose of this Privacy Policy? | This Privacy Policy tells you about the personal data we collect and what we do with it. | Section 1  
Who controls your personal data? | Your personal data is controlled by Aston Villa Football Club Limited and / or Aston Villa Foundation. | Section 2  
What is the legal basis for using your personal data? | We may use your personal data for a number of reasons. In particular:  
\- to perform a contract with you;  
\- because we have a legitimate interest to do so;  
\- because you have agreed (consented);  
\- to comply with the law | Section 3   
What personal data does the Club hold about you and how do we use it? |  We collect a variety of personal data in connection with:  
- your registration and use of our websites or mobile applications;  
\- any products or services provided by the Club that you purchase or use;  
\- any marketing preference you have given to us;  
\- any visit to our premises;   
\- any other communication you may have with us | Section 4   
Who do we share your personal data with? |  We may share your personal data with third parties. Including:  
\- our service providers;  
\- other companies within our group;  
\- law enforcement agencies;  
\- other football clubs;  
\- Official Lions Clubs;  
\- certain other third parties; and / or  
\- where required by law

Some third parties that we share personal data with may be based outside of the European Economic Area (EEA).

| Section 5   
Will we change the purpose for which we process your personal data? | We only use your personal data for the purposes we collected it for or for another reason compatible with that purpose. | Section 6  
Do we operate automated decision making? | We do not operate automated decision making, but some third parties we work with may do. | Section 7  
What security measures do we put in place? | We have put in place appropriate security measures to prevent your personal data from being accidentally lost, used or accessed in an unauthorised way, altered or disclosed. | Section 8  
  
How long will we keep your information for? | We only retain personal data for as long as necessary to fulfil the purposes it was collected for. | Section 9  
What are your legal rights? | You have a number of legal rights in relation to personal data, including the rights to request access, correction and / or erasure and to object to certain processing. | Section 10  
What about children under 16? | We expect parents and guardians to supervise their children when they access the Club’s websites, mobile applications and other services provided by the Club. | Section 11   
Does the Club have a Data Protection Officer? | Yes. You can contact the Club’s DPO at [dpo@avfc.co.uk](mailto:%20dpo@avfc.co.uk) or using the postal address details given in section 2. | Section 12  
What about changes to this Privacy Policy? | We may change this Privacy Policy from time to time. Please check back for updates. | Section 13  

**1\. What is the purpose of this Privacy Policy?(Back to Top)**

Aston Villa Football Club Limited and Aston Villa Foundation (together “the Club”) are committed to protecting the privacy and security of your personal data.

This Privacy Policy aims to give you information on how the Club collects and processes your personal data through your use of the Club’s websites and/or other services. 

The Club’s websites and services include:

  * the Club’s Official Website at [www.avfc.co.uk](https://www.avfc.co.uk/);
  * the Club’s AVTV channel at [www.avfc.co.uk/avtv](https://www.avfc.co.uk/AVTV);
  * the Club’s Ticket Office (online at [tickets.avfc.co.uk](https://www.avfc.co.uk/Tickets), via phone or in store at the Ticket Office, Villa Park);
  * the Club’s Official Mobile Application;
  * the Club’s “Fan Score” Mobile Application; and
  * the Club’s official social media channels (including, for example, Facebook, Twitter, Instagram, YouTube, LinkedIn, Sina Weibo, YouKu, AudioBoo, Google+).

It is important that you read this Privacy Policy together with any other privacy policy, statement or fair processing notice we may provide on specific occasions when we are collecting or processing personal data about you so that you are fully aware of how and why we are using your personal data. 

This Privacy Policy supplements any other notices we provide and is not intended to override them.

**2\. Who controls your personal data? ** (Back to Top)****

There are two different legal entities within the Club’s group of companies that process personal data: 

  * Aston Villa Football Club Limited (Company Number 03375789)
  * Aston Villa Foundation (Company Number 08589263; Charity Number 1152848)

This Privacy Policy is issued on behalf of these companies, so when we mention "the Club", "we", "us" or "our" in this Privacy Policy, we are referring to the relevant company in the Club’s group that is responsible for processing your personal data. 

Which company controls your personal data will depend on the way you interact with the Club or the services you are using. In most cases, Aston Villa Football Club Limited will be the data controller. 

Aston Villa Foundation runs the Club’s soccer schools, community benefit programmes and Fifty50 matchday raffle. When you use these services, or any other services offered by Aston Villa Foundation, then Aston Villa Foundation will be the data controller. 

Our contact details are:

Email address: [dpo@avfc.co.uk](mailto:%20dpo@avfc.co.uk)  
Postal address: Legal Department, Aston Villa Football Club, Villa Park, Birmingham, B6 6HE 

**

3\. The legal basis for using your personal data  ** **(Back to Top)****

There are a number of legal bases for using personal data. This section sets out more information on the main legal bases which the Club relies on. For further information on when each legal basis applies, please see section 4.

**

**_Performance of a contract with you_**

If we have entered into a contract with you, or are about to enter into a contract with you, we may need to process your personal data so that we can honour that contract. For example, if you buy tickets online we need to know your name and contact details so that we can send those tickets to you.

If you do not provide personal data that we need to perform a contract with you, we may not be able to perform that contract. This means that, where the contract is to provide you with a product or service, we may not be able to process your order or provide you with that product or service.

**_Legitimate interests_**

We may process your personal data where it is necessary for our interests (or those of a third party). We will only do this where: 

  * those interests are legitimate; AND
  * those interests are not overridden by your interests and fundamental rights.

You have the right to object to the processing of your personal data where we are processing that personal data as necessary for our legitimate interests. For more information, please see section 10.

**_Consent_**

If you have opted in to receive marketing information related to the Club, its products and services, or the products and services of its partners, we (or our partners) will process your personal data and contact you in accordance with your consent.

Click [HERE](https://d3ix52z2istd7h.cloudfront.net/~/media/00_Legal/PDFs/Aston%20Villa%20Football%20Club%20-%20List%20of%20Club%20partners%20-%2018%20September%202018.ashx?la=en&vs=1&d=20180919T133812Z) to see a list of our current partners.

We will only rely on consent when processing your personal data where you have clearly told us (or the third party that collected the personal data) that you consent to your personal data being processed by the Club. 

Where you may have provided your consent to the collection, processing and transfer of your personal data for a specific purpose, you have the right to withdraw your consent for that specific processing at any time. 

To withdraw your consent, you can:

  * follow the instructions provided in any relevant communication you have been given (for example, by logging into your account or clicking “unsubscribe” on a related email you have received); or
  * where such service is not available, contact the Club using the details provided in section 2. 

When doing this, please ensure that you provide sufficient information so that the Club can verify your identity and clearly state what you are withdrawing your consent to. If you withdraw your consent in this way, the Club may need to contact you to clarify your instructions – if you do not provide contact information then the Club may not be able to process your request if there are any relevant issues.

**_Legal obligation_**

We may need to process your personal data to comply with a legal or regulatory obligation.

**4\. The personal data the Club holds about you and how we use your personal data  ** **(Back to Top)******

Personal data means any information about an individual from which that person can be identified. It does not include data where the identity has been removed (anonymous data).

**_Information collected by the Club_**

__To see the full table on a mobile device without scrolling, rotate your mobile to landscape__

The Club may collect some or all of the following personal data about you and may use it as follows:

**Activity and the personal data we collect  ** | **Why we collect that personal data  ** | **The lawful basis for processing your personal data**  
---|---|---  
When you create an account with us or use our services, we will collect the identity and contact details that you provide us. This may include your name, title, date of birth, postal address, email address and telephone number(s). We will also collect your login information such as username and password. We may assign a unique identification number (known as a FanID) to your account. | To provide you with a personalised account when making use of the Club’s services.  
To provide you with information, products and services you have requested, to tell you about the status of requests or to resolve any issues that have arisen). | Performance of a contract / potential contract with you.   
Where you purchase a Matchday or season ticket (including half season tickets) from us, we collect details of your identity, contact details, account information, ticket purchase history and marketing preferences. | To provide you with tickets you have purchased and to maintain a record of your purchase history.  | Performance of a contract / potential contract with you.

Necessary for our legitimate interests (for sale of a ticket, to provide a dedicated seat and to control the number of individuals in the stadium; to ensure tickets for high demand fixtures are limited to active / loyal supporters and to support authorities (police, health and safety, football authorities) in delivering a safe and secure event; to study how supporters use our products/services; to develop them and to develop our business).   
  
Where you purchase tickets for away matches from us, we collect details of your identity, contact details, account information, ticket purchase history and marketing preferences. | To provide you with tickets you have purchased and to maintain a record of your purchase history.  
To provide other clubs with details of any away tickets you have purchased to attend their stadium. | Necessary for both our and the other club’s legitimate interests (ensuring supporters who have purchased valid tickets are permitted entry to the other club’s stadium, ensuring safety and security for all staff and visitors to the other club’s premises; to identify, protect against and report actual, potential or suspected fraud or criminal activity; to respond to claims).   
When purchasing a product or service from us we will also collect your payment card details and, if that purchase is not made in person (for example you purchase online or over the phone), we will also collect your billing address. We will also collect details of your historic payment method and purchase history. | To collect payment from you for products and services you have purchased.  | Performance of a contract / potential contract with you.

Necessary for our legitimate interests (to recover debts due to us).   
  
Where you sign up for auto renewal of your season ticket or automatic purchase of cup tickets and provide your payment card details and billing address, those details will be stored (by our third party payment gateway provider) for as long as you are a member of the relevant scheme (or until you update those payment details with new details). Once the details have been entered and provided to our third party payment gateway provider, the Club cannot access these details (they are masked). | To collect payment from you for products and services you have purchased.  | Performance of a contract / potential contract with you.

Necessary for our legitimate interests (to recover debts due to us).    
  
If you enter a competition, prize draw or other promotion that we may run, we will collect information that you may give us when you enter (or in any follow up communications we have with you), such as your name, Fan ID, contact details or social media handle(s), date of birth and proof of age (if relevant to entry), proof of address (if relevant to entry) and details of the prize won.  | To administer the competition, prize draw or promotion and (if you are successful) to provide you with your prize.  | Performance of a contract / potential contract with you.   
As you interact with our websites and mobile applications, or use our WIFI services,  
we automatically collect data about your equipment, network connection details, browsing actions and patterns. We collect this personal data by using cookies, and other similar technologies. We may also receive such information about you if you visit other websites employing our cookies. Please click [HERE](https://www.avfc.co.uk/club/legal/cookie-policy) to see our cookie policy for further details. | To use data analytics to improve our websites, products/services, marketing, information services, supporter relationships and experience. 

To study how supporters use our products/services, to develop them and to develop our business. 

To monitor the use of our WIFI network by guests visiting our premises.

| Necessary for our legitimate interests (to define types of supporters for our products and services; to study how supporters use our products/services; to keep our websites and products / services updated and relevant; to develop our business and inform our marketing strategy and information services strategy; for security).  
  
Where we communicate with you by email, we collect details of whether you opened that email and / or interacted with any of the content within that email. | To analyse, personalise and improve our communications, marketing, information services and supporter relationships.  | Necessary for our legitimate interests (to understand relevance of our email communications; to develop our supporter experience; to develop our business; and inform our marketing strategy and information services strategy).  
We may collect your age, contact details and marketing preferences to tell us how you prefer to be contacted when we communicate with you, or when you unsubscribe from receiving marketing communications. If you do not consent to any marketing, we also keep a record of this. | To send age appropriate marketing communications to supporters and to provide supporters with information services about the Club and products / services they have purchased.  | Consent

Necessary for our legitimate interests (to provide age appropriate information, information services and marketing to supporters, to grow our supporter database; to develop our business; and inform our marketing strategy and information services).   
  
We may collect your child’s name and age, photographs of them, film or video recordings of them, their medication details and your name, relationship to child and contact details in connection with your child’s mascot experience and for use in marketing communications. If you do not consent to any marketing, we will also keep a record of this.   
|  To administer the mascot experience, in particular if we need to contact you in the case of an emergency. For the child’s first name and image to be used in connection with publicity and marketing purposes for the Club to provide supporters with information services about the Club and its products and services. |  Performance of a contract / potential contract with you 

Consent

Necessary for our legitimate interests (to provide age appropriate information, information services and marketing to supporters, to grow our supporter database; to develop our business, ensuring safety and security for all staff and visitors to our premises; to respond to any claims and to claim from our insurers).

To comply with our legal obligations.  
  
If you contact us, for example with an enquiry, comment or complaint, we collect any personal information you may give in such correspondence with us. | To investigate, review and respond to your enquiry, comment or complaint. | Necessary for our legitimate interests (supporter relations; to improve our information services, products, services and supporter experience; and to develop our business).   
For security and safety of the Club and those visiting Club premises, the Club uses CCTV at Villa Park and its training ground at Bodymoor Heath and so if you attend either of those premises your image may be captured on CCTV recordings. The Club’s security staff and matchday stewards may also use body worn cameras which may also capture your image when attending our premises. | To monitor and review any accidents or incidents and for the safety and security of visitors to our premises.  | Necessary for our legitimate interests (ensuring safety and security for all staff and visitors to our premises; to improve our safety / security operations; to identify, protect against and report actual, potential or suspected fraud or criminal activity; to respond to claims).

To comply with our legal obligations.   
  
If you have an accident whilst at our premises, we may record details of your identity and contact details, as well as details of the accident, any injury sustained, treatment received and any other relevant factors or medical conditions. | To maintain a record of any accidents or incidents in line with legislation and good industry practice, for our insurance purposes and to protect the Club in the event of any future claims or legal action.  | Necessary for our legitimate interests (ensuring safety and security for all staff and visitors to our premises; to respond to any claims).

To comply with our legal obligations.  
  
If you are involved in any security related incident during a Matchday (whether at the Club’s stadium or at any other stadium or event which the Club participates in), we will keep details related to that incident, for example the identity and contact information of people involved or potential witnesses, details of the incident and copies of any relevant video footage. | To maintain a record of any accidents or incidents in line with legislation and good industry practice, for our insurance purposes and to protect the Club in the event of any future claims or legal action.  
| Necessary for our legitimate interests (ensuring safety and security for all staff and visitors to our premises; to improve our safety / security operations; to identify, protect against and report actual, potential or suspected fraud or criminal activity; to respond to claims; and to claim from our insurers).

To comply with our legal obligations.   
  
We may collect details of your identity (including image from CCTV or other camera footage) together with any relevant details of any convictions, orders, arrests or suspected involvement in incidents which may impact on the safety or security of any Matchdays or other events the Club takes part in. | To ensure safety and security for all staff and visitors to our premises. | Necessary for our legitimate interests (ensuring safety and security for all staff and visitors to our premises; to identify, protect against and report actual, potential or suspected fraud or criminal activity; to respond to claims; and to claim from our insurers).

To comply with our legal obligations.  
  
If you attend an event hosted or arranged by the Club, we may take photographs and / or film or video recordings of the event, which may include your image. |  For use in marketing materials and / or media coverage of the event.

Depending on the event, we may share these details with a third party (for example, Aston Villa Foundation may share copies of images with its grant funders, when the event was related to a grant funded project). We will tell you if we plan to do this and you will have the ability to opt out.

| Where consent is sought prior to or at the relevant event: consent.

Where the Club deems it inappropriate to seek consent prior to or at the relevant event: necessary for our legitimate interests (to develop our business).

Regardless of the basis upon which this personal data is processed, the Club will respect a request not to use your image in any future marketing materials.  
  
**Information received from third parties or publicly available sources**

We may also receive personal data about you from various third parties and public sources as set out below. Click [HERE](https://d3ix52z2istd7h.cloudfront.net/~/media/00_Legal/PDFs/Aston%20Villa%20Football%20Club%20-%20List%20of%203rd%20party%20service%20providers%20-%2018%20September%202018.ashx?la=en&vs=1&d=20180919T133811Z) to see a list of the names of our current third-party service providers.

_To see the full table on a mobile device without scrolling, rotate your mobile to landscape_

**Activity and the personal data we collect** | **Why we collect that personal data** | **The lawful basis for processing your personal data**  
---|---|---  
The Club’s official retail channels (which includes in store at Villa Park, over the phone, and online at shop.avfc.co.uk) are operated by Fanatics (International) Limited ("Fanatics"). When you buy products or services via those channels, we may receive information from Fanatics about your identity, contact details, purchase history and marketing preferences (only where you have given Fanatics consent to do so). | 

To market to you in line with your marketing preferences.

To study how supporters use our products/services, to develop them and to develop our business.

| 

Consent

Necessary for our legitimate interests (to study how supporters use our products and services; to develop our products and services; and to develop our business).

We may receive details of your identity, contact details, account information, ticket purchase history and marketing preferences from the provider of our Online Ticket Office and back office ticketing software. They will tell us if you have purchased a ticket to any match or event at the Club’s stadium or for an away match in which one of the Club’s teams takes part. | To provide you with tickets you have purchased and to maintain a record of your ticket purchase history.  | 

Performance of a contract / potential contract with you.

Necessary for our legitimate interests (to study how supporters use our products/services; to develop them and to develop our business).  
  
 If you access the Club’s WIFI service, we collect details of your identity (name, email address, post code, confirmation of being over 18) and marketing preferences as part of your registration for our WIFI service from the provider of our WIFI registration services.

Our third party provider also collects details of your browsing session, including the device and browser you are using and sites you visit whilst using our WIFI services..

| To provide you with WIFI access at the Club’s premises.

To market to you in line with your marketing preferences.

To analyse and understand who uses the Club’s WIFI services.

For security and monitoring to ensure compliance with the law and terms and conditions of use of the services provided.

| Performance of a contract / potential contract with you.

Consent

Necessary for our legitimate interests (supporter relations; to improve products / services / supporter experience and to develop our business; and to identify, protect against and report actual, potential or suspected fraud or breaches of our terms and conditions of service or criminal activity).  
  
In periods where we expect high demand for tickets (e.g. key matches or periods where season tickets go on sale), we may use the services of a call centre to assist us with ticket purchases over the telephone. Where this occurs, you may be directed to a call centre when you call the Club’s Ticket Office. They will collect your identity, contact and payment details and provide them to us / our Ticket Office software provider to process the purchase. | To ensure your call is answered as quickly as possible; and to provide you with tickets you have purchased.   | 

Performance of a contract / potential contract with you.

Necessary for our legitimate interests (to study how supporters use our products/services; to develop them and to develop our business).  
  
We may receive details of your identity, contact details and account information received from the provider of our Pride Rewards scheme and e-cash scheme to tell us about your membership and use of the scheme (including products / services you have purchased from third party affiliates using your Pride Rewards e-cash card).  | To administer the Pride Rewards and E-cash scheme.

To analyse and understand how supporters use the Pride Rewards and E-cash scheme. 

| Performance of a contract / potential contract with you.

Necessary for our legitimate interests (supporter relations; and to improve products / services / supporter experience and to develop our business).    
  
We may receive details of your identity, contact details and transaction information from our secondary ticketing partner to tell us about any tickets you have purchased or sold on our official secondary ticketing platform.  | To process any ticket sale / purchase made through our secondary ticketing partner.  |  Performance of a contract / potential contract with you.   
When you use your Matchday ticket, season card or membership card to gain access to the Club’s facilities services at Villa Park (the Club’s stadium), we receive details of usage of your tickets from the providers of our stadium access control system.  | To provide you with access to the Club’s stadium (Villa Park) and the Club’s facilities / services.

To analyse and understand how and when our supporters use our facilities / services. 

| Performance of a contract / potential contract with you.

Necessary for our legitimate interests (supporter relations; and to improve products / services / supporter experience and to develop our business).    
  
When you purchase a product or service, we receive your contact details, payment details and details of the transaction from our payment gateway provider.  | To collect payment from you for products and services you have purchased.  | Performance of a contract / potential contract with you.

Necessary for our legitimate interests (to recover debts due to us).  
  
If you have an accident whilst at our premises and are treated by a third party (for example, St John’s Ambulance), we may receive details of your identity and contact details, as well as details of the accident, any injury sustained, treatment administered and any other relevant factors or medical conditions.  
| To maintain a record of any accidents or incidents in line with legislation and good industry practice, for our insurance purposes and to protect the Club in the event of any future claims or legal action. | Necessary for our legitimate interests (ensuring safety and security for all staff and visitors to our premises; to respond to any claims; and to claim from our insurers).

To comply with our legal obligations.   
  
We may receive details of your identity from government and law enforcement authorities, together with any relevant details of any convictions, orders, arrests or suspected involvement in incidents which may impact on the safety or security of any Matchdays or other events the Club takes part in. | To ensure safety and security for all staff and visitors to our premises. | Necessary for our legitimate interests (ensuring safety and security for all staff and visitors to our premises; to identify, protect against and report actual, potential or suspected fraud or criminal activity; to respond to claims).

To comply with our legal obligations.   
  
If you are an away fan attending the Club’s stadium (Villa Park) and have purchased your tickets via the away club, we may receive details of your name and ticket details from that away club.  
| To ensure safety and security for all staff and visitors to our premises. |  Necessary for both our and the away club’s legitimate interests (ensuring supporters who have purchased valid tickets are permitted entry to the Club’s stadium, ensuring safety and security for all staff and visitors to our premises; to identify, protect against and report actual, potential or suspected fraud or criminal activity; to respond to claims.  
When you agree to receive notifications from our websites, our third party notification services provider will collect information about your device, the pages on our websites that you visited, the start and end time of your websites session(s) and the location of your device when visiting our websites. This information is collected on an anonymised basis (whilst this information is linked to the device you used, we do not link that information to an individual or an IP address).  
| To provide tailored notifications to you based on your websites usage, device type and location (subject to you providing your consent to receive notifications).   
|  Consent  
  
If you agree to take part in an online Club survey or other data capture exercise hosted by a third party (for example, Survey Monkey), the Club will receive the information that you provide as part of that survey.  
| To review and analyse the results of the survey or other data capture exercise. To administer any prize draws or competitions that are related to the survey or other data capture exercise. There may also be other purposes for collecting the personal data, which will be specified within the form used to collect the personal data.  
| Generally, the lawful basis for processing personal data captured via a survey or other data capture exercise will be consent.

There may a separate lawful basis – if so, details will be set out in the form used to collect the personal data.  
  
Specialist data providers provide us with profile information about our supporters. We use this to segment and understand our supporters.

Currently, we use Experian Limited to do this – you can visit their websites and view their privacy policy at www.experian.co.uk).

| To understand supporter preferences. To provide supporters with relevant information and improve our products and services.  
| Necessary for our legitimate interests (supporter relations; and to improve products / services / supporter experience and to develop our business).  
  
Data analytics providers provide us with: (a) data on supporters’ behaviour on our websites and mobile applications (e.g. how much time supporters spend on which pages / sections, which links they choose to click, what supporters do and don’t like, etc.); and (b) devices used to access our websites and mobile applications (in particular device's IP address (in an anonymised form), screen size, type (unique device identifiers), browser data, geographic location (country only), preferred language).

Currently we use Hotjar Limited to do this for website data and Shift6 Limited (trading as “AppSee”) for mobile application data. 

Hotjar, AppSee and the Club will never use this information to identify individual supporters or to match it with further data on an individual supporter.

For further details, please see Hotjar’s website and privacy policy at [www.hotjar.com](http://www.hotjar.com/) and AppSee’s website and privacy policy at www.appsee.com

| To understand the needs of supporters and to optimise service and experience.  
| Necessary for our legitimate interests (supporter relations; and to improve products / services / supporter experience and to develop our business).  

**5\. Sharing personal data with third parties  ** **(Back to Top)****  
**

The Club may share your personal data with third parties, including other entities in the wider Club Group, where required by law, where it is necessary to administer the working relationship with you or where the Club has another legitimate interest in doing so. 

**_Transfers to Third Party Service Providers  _**

The Club uses third parties to help us provide you with products and services. We will share your personal details with those third parties where it is relevant to the service we are providing to you. Details of the Club’s third party service providers can be found [HERE](https://d3ix52z2istd7h.cloudfront.net/~/media/00_Legal/PDFs/Aston%20Villa%20Football%20Club%20-%20List%20of%203rd%20party%20service%20providers%20-%2018%20September%202018.ashx?la=en&vs=1&d=20180919T133811Z). 

**_Transfers within the Club’s group of companies_**

The Club may share your personal data with other entities in its group as part of its regular reporting activities on Club performance, in the context of a Club reorganisation or restructuring exercise, for system maintenance support and hosting of data. 

**_Transfers to the police_**

We may share information with the police or other law enforcement or governmental agencies where necessary for:

  * maintaining safety and security at the Club’s premises and matches and other events that the Club takes part in; or 
  * the prevention or detection of crime or the apprehension or prosecution of offenders.

_  
**Transfers to other football clubs**_

We may share ticketing information with other football clubs where the Club is taking part in a match at their stadium, to ensure that any issues with the Club’s travelling fans who have purchased tickets can be resolved quickly and easily or do address any safety or security issues which may arise. 

**_Transfers to Lions Clubs / chairman_**

If you create an account on the Club’s official website to register to join an Official Lions Club, we will pass your information (name and email address) to that Lions Club as part of your application. The Lions Club will be the data controller of that information in respect of anything that Lions Club does with it. The Lions Club will tell us whether or not your application is successful and we will contact you to tell you. If successful, we will keep a record of this so that we can give you access to any Club benefits you may be entitled to receive as an Official Lions Club member.

**_Transfers to other third parties_**

The Club may share your personal data with other third parties, for example in the context of the possible sale or restructuring of the Club’s business. In this situation the Club will, so far as possible, share anonymised data with the other parties before the transaction completes. Once the transaction is completed, the Club will share your personal data with the other parties if and to the extent required under the terms of the transaction. 

The Club may also need to share your personal data with a regulator or to otherwise comply with the law.

**_Transfers outside the European Economic Area (EEA)_**

This may occur when the third party that we share your data with is situated outside the European Economic Area (which is made up of the countries forming the European Union, plus Iceland, Liechtenstein and Norway), or they use servers or other cloud services based outside the EU. If the Club does so, the Club will do its best to ensure a similar degree of protection in respect of your personal data as if the transfer was made within the EEA.

**_Ensuring security when transferring personal data to third parties_**

All of the Club’s third-party service providers and other entities in the Club’s group are required to take appropriate security measures to protect your personal data in line with the Club’s policies and the law and to treat the information confidentially. The Club does not allow the Club’s third-party service providers to use your personal data for their own purposes. The Club only permits them to process your personal data for specified purposes and in accordance with the Club’s instructions. 

**6\. Change of Purpose  ** ** **(Back to Top)********

The Club will only use your personal data for the purposes for which we collected it, unless the Club reasonably considers that it needs to use it for another reason and that reason is compatible with the original purpose. If the Club needs to use your personal data for an unrelated purpose, the Club will notify (by updating this Privacy Policy) and explain the legal basis for doing so. 

Please note that the Club may process your personal data without your knowledge or consent, in compliance with the above rules, where this is required or permitted by law.

**7\. Automated Decision-Making  ** ** **(Back to Top)********

The Club does not currently operate any automated decision-making. 

Please note that Zebra Finance, the company which offers a finance solution for the Club’s season ticket purchasers may use automated decision-making when deciding whether or not to offer you credit. The Club has no influence or involvement in this. Please refer to Zebra Finance’s website for further information. Zebra Finance’s Privacy Notice can be found [HERE](http://www.zebrafinance.com/privacynotice) (please note this will take you to a third party website – the Club is not responsible for Zebra Finance’s website).

**8\. Data Security  ** ** **(Back to Top)********

The Club has put in place appropriate security measures to prevent your personal data from being accidentally lost, used or accessed in an unauthorised way, altered or disclosed. In addition, the Club limits access to your personal data to those employees, agents, consultants and other third parties (referred to in section 5) who have a business need to know. They will only process your personal data on the Club’s instructions and they are subject to a duty of confidentiality. 

The Club has put in place procedures to deal with any data security breach and will notify you and any applicable regulator of a breach where the Club is legally required to do so.

**9\. How long will the Club keep your information for?  ** ** **(Back to Top)********

The Club will only retain your personal data for as long as necessary to fulfil the purposes it collected it for, including for the purposes of satisfying any legal, accounting, or reporting requirements. The Club has in place a Data Retention Policy which includes recommended data retention periods for your personal data. 

In some circumstances the Club may anonymise your personal data so that it can no longer be associated with you, in which case the Club may use such information without further notice to you. 

  * We keep information related to your Official AVFC Website account for as long as your account remains active. To delete your Official AVFC Website Account, please contact the Club using the details provided in section 2.
  * We keep supporter personal data in our Club database for the longer of: 
    * 2 years from the supporter’s last known interaction with the Club; or
    * in the case of Club ticket purchases, 5 seasons since the last purchase.
As we review our databases on a quarterly basis, personal data may be retained for slightly longer than the periods specified above, until the next quarterly review. 
  * Where you have opted in to receive marketing, we retain details of your consent and shall continue to market to you in accordance with your preferences for a period of 2 years from your last interaction with the Club or until you opt out, whichever is earlier.
  * For the purposes of retaining personal data, we currently regard the following as interactions with the Club: attending a Club match; logging into your online account; purchasing a product from the Club’s Online Store; opening an email from the Club. We may update this from time to time, depending on the data available to the Club to capture interactions.
  * We keep information which may relate to accidents or injuries for a period of 3 years from the date of the last entry in the log in which it is recorded (or, where the accident involves a child/ young adult, until that person reaches the age of 21, if longer). We do this in case there are any queries and to respond to any claims in relation to that incident. If we are aware that claim or legal action is or ongoing in relation to an accident or injury, we will keep relevant information until that claim or legal action has concluded.
  * We keep other information which may relate to a claim or legal action for a period of 7 years (or longer, if a claim or legal action is in progress). We do this in case there are any queries and to respond to claims in relation to that incident.
  * We keep CCTV footage for a period of 28 days following the recording (or longer if required in connection with an ongoing issue or if required by law).

**10\. Your legal rights  ** ** **(Back to Top)********

It is important that the personal data the Club holds about you is accurate and current. Please keep the Club informed if your personal data changes. 

Under certain circumstances, by law you have the right to:

  * Request access to your personal data (commonly known as a "data subject access request"). This enables you to receive a copy of the personal data the Club holds about you and to check that it is lawfully processing it.
  * Request correction of the personal data that the Club holds about you. This enables you to have any incomplete or inaccurate information the Club holds about you corrected.
  * Request erasure of your personal data. This enables you to ask the Club to delete or remove personal data where there is no good reason for it continuing to process it. You also have the right to ask the Club to delete or remove your personal data where you have exercised your right to object to processing (see below).
  * Object to processing of your personal data where the Club is relying on a legitimate interest (see section 3 for those circumstances) (or those of a third party) and there is something about your particular situation which makes you want to object to processing on this ground. We may be able to continue processing even if you object (if we have compelling legitimate grounds which override your interests, rights and freedoms or if in connection with legal claims).
  * Object to processing where the Club is processing your personal data for direct marketing purposes. 
  * Request the restriction of processing of your personal data. This enables you to ask the Club to suspend the processing of personal data about you, for example if you want the Club to establish its accuracy or the reason for processing it.
  * Request the transfer of your personal data to another party. 
  * Withdraw consent at any time where we are relying on consent to process your personal data. However, this will not affect the lawfulness of any processing carried out before you withdraw your consent or of any processing that is lawfully carried out for another purpose (for example, to comply with a contract or a legitimate interest). If you withdraw consent, we may not be able to provide certain products or services to you. We will advise you if this is the case at the time you withdraw your consent.

If you want to review, verify, correct or request erasure of your personal data, object to the processing of your personal data, or request that the Club transfers a copy of your personal data to another party, please contact the Club in writing using the contact details given in section 2. Please ensure you give us details of your identity and contact details so we can identify you and the personal data in question and contact you in relation to your query.

You will not have to pay a fee to access your personal data (or to exercise any of the other rights). However, the Club may charge a reasonable fee if your request for access is clearly unfounded or excessive. Alternatively, the Club may refuse to comply with the request in such circumstances.

The Club may need to request specific information from you to help it confirm your identity and ensure your right to access the information (or to exercise any of your other rights). This is to ensure that personal data is not disclosed to any person who has no right to receive it.  
**  
11\. Children under the age of 16  ** ** **(Back to Top)********

We expect parents and guardians to supervise their child when they access the Club’s websites, mobile applications and other services provided by the Club's websites, 

If you are under the age of 16, you must ask your parent / guardian for consent before you access the Club’s services or provide personal data or other information to the Club.

**12\. Data Protection Officer  ** ** **(Back to Top)********

The Club’s designated Data Protection Officer ([dpo@avfc.co.uk](mailto:%20dpo@avfc.co.uk)) will oversee compliance with this Privacy Policy. If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy or how the Club handles your personal data, please contact the Club using the details given in section 2.

Whilst we hope you would contact the Club (using the details provided in section 2) with any issues first, you have the right to make a complaint at any time to the Information Commissioner's Office (“ICO”), the UK supervisory authority for data protection issues. You can contact the ICO online [HERE](http://ico.org.uk/), or by post at:

Information Commissioner's Office  
Wycliffe House  
Water Lane  
Wilmslow  
Cheshire  
SK9 5AF

**13\. Changes to this Privacy Policy  ** ** **(Back to Top)********

We will update this Privacy Policy from time to time, so please check this Privacy Policy periodically, so you are aware of any updates. The date below records when this Privacy Policy was last updated.

February 2019
